The following content is provided under a Creative
Commons license.
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare
continue to offer high-quality educational resources for free.
To make a donation or to view additional materials
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
The first thing I would like to tell you,
which I did not mention the last time,
that in the reading assignment, the syllabus that we handed out,
and by the way, does everybody have one?
If you don't, we have some extras here.
You all have one.
Good.
Anyway, as you can see on the first page,
there is a section called preparatory reading.
So I would recommend that if you can,
to each time read this recommended reading, which
is available, of course, on the internet,
and that will make it easier for you to follow the lecture.
Because this course, as both in vision and in audition,
relies on imparting a great many facts
about the work use of these two systems.
And it's easier to be able to memorize these facts
by doing the preparatory reading if you can.
All right, so today, then, what we are going to do
is we're going to initially start
to talk about the layout of the visual system.
And then we're going to talk about the retina
for much of the course.
At the very end, we'll talk a little bit
about the lateral geniculate nucleus.
In each case, I will try to tell you
about how some people have thought about things
and what the progression is of the discoveries that
had been made about the visual system.
It is certainly an area of research
which has been incredibly successful
and has resulted in quite a number of Nobel prizes
for the discoveries that individuals
had made in uncovering the workings of this system.
Furthermore, many of the uncoverings
that investigators had done came about as incredible surprises
because so many of the findings were quite unexpected.
And I will try to point these things out during the course.
And my section, as I've mentioned before,
will consist of 12 lectures.
And then that will be followed on October 23
by a midterm exam.
And again, to reiterate, that's going
to consist of a series of multiple-choice questions.
And then following that, we'll move on
to talk about the auditory system that Chris Brown is going
to be presenting to you.
All right, so the first thing I want
to do then is to talk about the basic wiring
of the visual system, which in itself
has yielded a number of unexpected surprises
and also raised some interesting questions.
So what I want to start with, first of all,
is that when you look at some animals that
have sideways-looking eyes, like the rabbit and most amphibia,
the two eyes look out in two different directions,
to the left and to the right.
And that enables them to see a very large portion
of the visual field.
And when that is the case, as in this picture shown here
for the rabbit, what you find is that there's only
a small area which is seen by both eyes.
But then when we look at higher mammals,
and particularly primates and humans,
what you find that there was a huge change
in the course of evolution bringing the eyes to the front.
Now, that change is very interesting.
And we can ask, why on earth did that happen?
Because it meant that, obviously, a human cannot see
behind themselves where these rabbits can see a much larger
portion of the visual field.
And so you sacrifice the ability to see all the way
around the world for being able to see with both eyes
to the front.
And so the question is, why did this happen?
Now, we are going to discuss this in some detail,
because one of the prime reasons, I believe at least,
that this has happened is to be able to process information
about depth better than it can be done by rabbits
and other animals.
And so when we talk about depth perception,
we are going to deal with this issue in more detail.
Now, if you look at an animal like a rabbit, what you find
and also animals, which, as I've mentioned already,
sorry, I'm going backwards here, that you also
have an efficient amphibia.
You have these sideways-looking eyes.
And now we can ask the question, how do these two eyes
make their connections through the ganglion cells
to the central nervous system?
And that, in fact, was quite an issue at one time,
believe it or not, before anatomical techniques
became more sophisticated.
And the reason it became an issue is
because it was discovered predominantly actually
by Kahal, who I have mentioned had received the Nobel Prize
for the beautiful work he had done on not only the vision,
but in general about the nervous system in 1906 with Golgi.
He discovered, as did several other investigators,
that the optic nerve crosses over at the so-called chiasm.
And so the input from the left eye
projects into the right half of the brain
and from the right eye to the left half of the brain.
And that became a huge issue.
Why on earth would this happen?
And we are going to deal with this repeatedly.
It's a very interesting issue.
And even more interesting is the fact
that when the eyes move to the front, what happened
is that this kind of connection became much more complicated.
But before I do that, let me just say a few more words here.
First of all, that in fission amphibia,
you have a huge structure called the optic tectum, which
is the primary visual processing center in the brain.
And there is also the lateral genital nucleus
of the thalamus in these animals,
but that's quite small and not very well developed.
And there is a cortex in these animals,
but it is, again, a primitive area
compared to primates, for example.
And the lateral genital nucleus projects to the cortex.
So the left cortex in these animals
gets input from the right eye.
And the obverse is the case for the right cortex.
And so consequently, this cortex
sees this part of the visual field
and this cortex sees this part of the visual field.
It's almost like an inversion.
Now, we come to what happened as a result of the eyes
moving to the front.
And the eyes move to the front in the course of evolution
that necessitated a major rewiring in the visual system.
So that's what we are going to look at next, because that's
us, all right?
So what we have here then, we have the two eyes
looking to the front.
And imagine that these two eyes now looking at something.
There's a dot here.
And both eyes are looking at the same dot
so that you only see a single dot.
So now what happens is really something surprising.
What happens is that the, let me interrupt for a second
and tell you that imagine that you cut your eye,
I mean, don't do it, but imagine that you
cut your eye vertically in half, each eye, OK?
And that means that each eye has, if you will,
a nasal half and a temporal half, all right?
So here we have the two eyes.
Here's the left eye.
And what we have is a nasal half projects across.
And the same thing is true for the right eye, projects across.
But now if you look at the temporal hemiratne,
hemiratne, remember, that's the word for it,
something very interesting happens.
The temporal hemiratne don't cross over,
but they remain on the same side.
So we have a color code here that the red parts
project across, and the black parts also
project across from one eye, but stay
ipsilateral for the other eye.
So you say, my god, why did this happen?
What on earth is going on?
And then if you study this, you realize
that this is actually one of the few truly logical things
that you encounter when you study the brain.
Many of the things you study in the brain
don't seem to be too logical, because in the force of evolution,
you have to change things in very peculiar subtle ways
to make things work.
You couldn't just redo the whole system from scratch.
But this is certainly a logical one,
and I'll explain it to you in just a minute.
OK, so now what we do next is that, again, we
have the two-level genically nuclei,
but now these are in the thalamus.
These two nuclei have grown tremendously in size
and became much more important in visual processing,
as did then the cortex.
This process, by the way, is called encephalization.
So in primitive animals, you have very small cortex,
and then in the course of evolution, the cortex
grew and grew and grew and grew and became
a more and more important structure
in being able to analyze just about anything
and certainly analyze vision.
Now here we have a cortical area in the posterior part
of the brain, as I pointed out to you the last time.
And what we have is a whole series of visual areas
in the cortex.
Most central one, I guess, would be area V1,
the primary so-called primary visual cortex,
to which the lateral genically it projects most profusely.
Then we have a whole bunch of other visual areas,
as we'll discuss in more detail later on.
And then what happens is that we have several other cortical
areas.
The cortex, I think all of you know that,
is divided into four lobes, the frontal, temporal, parietal,
and the rear one is called the occipital lobes.
Now the visual areas that you see in the back here
make extensive interconnections and connections
to these other lobes in the brain
to be able to analyze the visual scene.
Now in addition, what we have still,
as we had in more primitive animals,
we have a superior colliculus, actually two of them,
one on each side.
And then we have another set of areas
called the terminal nuclei, the nucleus of the optic tract,
about which we'll just talk a little bit,
because they are specializing in certain visual functions,
but not nearly as compelling and interesting
as the work that has been done in the cortical areas
and in the superior colliculi.
So this is the arrangement.
But now we want to understand, why
do we have this strange connection here?
So to understand that, what we are going to talk about
is the so-called choropter or the Wieth-Miller circle.
Now what does that?
Some clever guy came up with this observation.
They made a circle that goes through the nodal point of the eye,
and its diameter depends on where you are fixating.
So fixating here, all right?
And so in this case, the red area,
which is your left visual hemifield,
impinges on the nasal retina of the left eye
and the temporal retina of the other eye.
So if you have an object here, all right,
that hits corresponding retinal elements in the two eyes.
And that is the basic rule.
Anywhere along this choropter, a spot
will activate corresponding regions in the two eyes.
And then what happens is that those corresponding points
go to the same location in the lateral geniculate nucleus
and the superior coliculus and in the visual cortex.
So the logic of this arrangement
is to be able to have the two eyes have
inputs to corresponding points in the brain.
That way you can see something uniform and clear
rather than seeing double.
So that is then the arrangement that you have in primates.
Now just to anticipate a little bit,
whenever images fall inside or outside the circle,
they do fall on non-correspondent points.
And that will have something to do.
And I keep you just curious about that for the time being
about how we process depth.
And that is the mechanism that is involved.
It's called stereopsis.
I've mentioned that very briefly the last time.
OK, so that then summarizes the basic connections
of the system.
And then what we are going to do next
is we're going to go to the retina
and look at it in more details about how the retina is made.
And then we will go in successive steps to higher areas,
sometimes going back and forth, to try
to understand visual processing in general.
All right, so now let's begin by looking at the eye.
Now I don't expect you to know all these names here.
But you should remember, of course, the lens and the cornea.
I know that already.
You know the iris, right?
What's the iris?
OK, now what do we base our views on the color of the eye?
When you say somebody has blue eyes or somebody has brown eyes,
it's based on the fact of what the coloring is of the iris.
Now what's the iris?
The iris can get bigger and smaller
to control the size of the opening into the lens.
All right?
It's much like what you have in cameras
where you have the so-called f-stop, right?
So if you have a large number, say f-16 in a camera,
that is set to 16 if you do it manually
or when it's bright out there.
But when it's dim out there, like we have in this camera here,
you have the lens wide open because it's pretty dark in here.
Then you have a low f-stop, like an f-4 or even lower,
to allow more light to come in, to more photons to enter the eye.
Now, next is here's the lens.
And the fascinating thing about the lens
is that in the eye, the lens is totally different
from the way it is in a camera.
Now, maybe by now, many of you don't even
know the details about a camera.
But one of the details, of course,
is that to bring an image into focus,
you have to adjust the distance of the lens
from the film onto which the image projects.
So the closer an image, the further out the lens has to go.
Now, if that were the case in animals and humans,
you would have a super bulging eye.
So when you look at something closely,
the eye would go out like that.
And that would be really disturbing.
So that is not the case because what happened instead
is something very clever that you don't see in cameras, which
is that you have this lens here, which is, at least
in younger people, is an organ that can vary in thickness.
So you have here some muscles, the ciliary muscles, which
can adjust the thickness of this lens
to allow it to focus properly on the retina.
Now, here the retina is going all around.
It's against the inner wall of the eye, as you all know that,
of course.
And to explain how this is done then very crudely,
here we have it.
If you're an object really near, you
want the lens to be thick to properly focus the image
on the retina.
And if the image is far, you have
to thin the lens to get the proper focus on the retina.
So that's how the lens works, at least
when you're reasonably young.
But then when you get older, what happens
is that the lens becomes progressively stiffer and stiffer.
And because of that, you have to start wearing glasses.
Now, in the olden days, they used to have lenses which came
in two parts, bifocals.
So if you look in the upper part,
you could look in the distance.
If you look in the lower part, you could look close.
Nowadays, they have graduated lenses.
So if you look in the upper part, you can look far.
And if you want to look something,
you're going to look down below.
And then you can see that in focus.
So once you get older, these lenses
don't adjust as much, still a little bit.
But the proof that this is not that important, thank God,
now that we have these graded lenses and we have bifocals,
is that there are a lot of people in old age who develop,
and sometimes not even in old age.
In India, for example, there are a lot
of young kids who have cataracts.
Now, what is cataracts?
Cataracts interferes with the processing of vision
through the lens system.
Things become unclear because all kinds of blockage
occur in the lens itself.
So how is that corrected?
The way that's corrected nowadays,
that you have what is called cataract surgery.
Got it?
Cataract surgery.
So what they do then is they actually, literally,
remove the lens from the eye.
And they put in a fixed lens made out of plastic or glass.
And then, obviously, since there's no adjustment,
you do have to wear glasses to look at things far away
and look at things close.
And most of the time, those would be graduated lenses.
And so people who have cataract surgery
can see extremely well, certainly a lot, lot better
than having to try to deal with lenses that have cataracts.
All right, now, there's one other point
I want to make about the eye here before we move on.
Maybe two points.
One is that about this part of the eye,
that you have here your so-called iris.
And what do you call what's in the center of the iris?
Pupil, very good.
Now, what is the color of the pupil?
In most people, it's black, right?
Why is it black?
How come the pupil is black?
Any thoughts about that?
OK, well, let me tell you.
And I think what I'll do is actually I'll move on.
First, I'll leave this unanswered for just a few minutes.
This I've shown you before, which
is another amazing thing about the eye,
is, namely, that in the fovea, you
have something like 200,000 cones per square millimeter.
200,000.
As you go 5 degrees out, it reduces 10 fold to 20,000.
And then you go 10 degrees, it reduces by half.
So because of this very high density,
I've mentioned this before, in the fovea,
you have high acuity.
And that is one of the prime reasons
you have to move your eye around so that you
can see things in fine detail.
All right, so now let's take another step here
and look at the retina itself.
And let me, first of all, point out to you
I have reversed the image here to have it right side up.
The light actually comes in from the bottom,
goes through all these cells until it hits the photoreceptors.
Here are the photoreceptors.
And at the closest point to the eye,
what we have is called the pigment epithelium.
OK, so what's the pigment epithelium?
The pigment epithelium is a single layer of cells
that are pigmented to such a degree
that when photons come into the eye
and get to the pigment epithelium,
they get absorbed just like a black surface
that you see as a black surface absorbs the photons
and doesn't reflect them.
So because of that, there is no reflection back out.
And that explains why the pupil looks black, OK?
Because the light that comes into the eye
doesn't reflect back out.
Now there's a good reason for that,
because if it were to reflect back out, it would scatter
and it would activate many more photoreceptors than it should.
And because of that, you get blurred vision.
Now how do we know this?
All right.
Can you think of any one or any species of animal
where the pigment epithelium is not black?
OK, in cat.
OK, so there are some animals.
You see mostly in animals that specialize
in nocturnal vision that have a pigment epithelium which
actually has purposefully reflecting molecules in it.
For them, this is called actually the terpetum.
And the purpose of that is to improve your ability
to see so that the photons activate the photoreceptors
not only in one direction, but also when they bounce back.
Now the terpetum is arranged in such a way in most animals
that it doesn't freely scatter the light,
but scatters it in a fairly directional manner.
And because of that, you can see pretty well.
Now, I'm sure that many of you have noticed
that when you drive at night in a deserted area
in the United States, which are decreasing, of course,
you can see sometimes deer on the highway or rabbits,
for that matter.
And when you see them, it looks like they
have two flashlights projecting at you.
It's almost scary, but it also helps you
by being able to avoid hitting them.
Now that's because they have that reflecting terpetum.
Let's look at a different example.
What other human can you think of who
does not have a black pigment epithelium?
Or, for that matter, some animals as well, yes?
Very good.
Albinos.
Now what's albinos?
Albinos are individuals or animals
who lack pigments in their skin and, of course,
in their retinae.
So if you look at the eye of an albino,
actually their pupil is not black.
Their pupil is reddish.
Very good.
Why is it reddish?
Because you have thousands of, in the retinae rightal law,
especially mostly on the outside here as well,
you have blood vessels.
And the blood vessels, since they carry blood,
when light reflects from them, they will have a reddish color
to them, and thereby endow, if you will, the pupil
with a reddish color.
Now the proof that the main function of the pigment
epithelium is to absorb the incoming light
to prevent scattering is in the fact
that albinos that lack this pigment epithelium
have very poor vision.
They often have vision to 20 over 200 or something,
because the light scatters from the epithelium, which
is no longer pigmented in these people,
and activates many photoreceptors,
thereby reducing the ability to see things clearly and sharply.
All right, so now let's go through this retina here.
First of all, we have the rods and the cones.
Now this brings me to a very interesting story, at least
for me an interesting story.
Back in the 19th century, there was a person whose name was,
let's see, his name was Max Schulze.
I'm trying to remember when he lived.
He lived from 1825 to 1874.
He developed some new anatomical procedures.
And as I mentioned before, whenever new techniques emerge
or invented, it's likely that you're
going to make some interesting new discoveries.
And so he was the first person by then looking at the retina
and looking at the photoreceptors,
that he said, my god, there are two different kinds of cones.
I shouldn't say cones.
Two different kinds of photoreceptors,
the rods and the cones, all right?
The rods were sort of like the name implies rods,
and the cones were sort of, as the name implies, conish.
Looking, OK?
So he looked at that and looked at that and said, my god,
why on earth would we have in most animals, rods, and cones?
What is their function?
This was a totally new discovery.
And when he first published this, nobody believed him.
They said, oh, they just vary randomly,
and some are more rod-like, some are more cone-like.
But it's just the same photoreceptors.
So he, of course, did not accept that.
He saw, by being very careful about it,
that it was two definitely different classes,
just like it is in this picture.
And so he began to ask the question, why on earth
do we have this?
So imagine yourself in the 19th century
coming up with this incredible discovery
and trying to figure out why we have them.
Now, if you're a really good scientist,
then you start to think analytically.
And so what did he do?
I'm so impressed to this day.
He said, well, let me take a closer look at the retina
and see how the rods and the cones are distributed
on the retinal surface.
And he discovered, to go back to the previous slide,
that there is a small region here, the fovea,
where there are only cones.
There are no rods.
I'll now show you a better picture of that in a minute.
And he said, my god, if that's the case,
there must be something different about the way
we see in the fovea than we can see in areas
where we have lots of rods.
So what did he discover?
He discovered that in the fovea,
we don't see too well at night.
And the basis of that, he concluded
that the rods are for night vision.
Now, this was absolutely incredible.
There's only one sad part in this story,
which is that this discovery was made in the early 19th century
before the Nobel Prize was initiated.
Because had the Nobel Prize been initiated
before he made this discovery, there's no question
that he would have received the Nobel Prize for it.
It's such an incredible magnitude of discovery.
All right, so let's go back here, then.
And I pointed out the rods and the cones
and the pigment epithelium.
Now, let's go through here.
And I'll tell you about the rest of the elements.
And then, this time and also in several subsequent sessions,
we will talk about some of these elements
in much more detail, especially about the retinal ganglion
cells.
So anyway, when you come here to the next stage here,
we have the so-called horizontal cells and bipolar cells.
It's been established that the photoreceptors
connect with both of these.
And then, the bipolar cells connect
into the inner portion of the retina,
just as I'll show you in a minute.
Now, this region here is called the OPL.
And that's easy to remember, outer plexiform layer.
Now, then, when you get into the deeper parts of the retina,
you have the so-called emercrine cells and ganglion cells.
And they reside in the inner plexiform layer.
Now, it is the ganglion cells that project out of the eye
and then project, as we had shown you,
to various regions in the brain, most notably,
that we're going to talk about today,
the lateral geniculate nucleus.
Now, let me also point out at this stage.
Let me see.
Do I have a picture of that?
I'll point out to you some numbers.
Here is an enlarged, highly simplified view of rods.
Now, the rods are constructed in an incredibly complex way.
They have these individual so-called disks.
And within each of these disks, there are about 1,000 of them.
I only have 25 here, I think, of 24.
There are about 1,000 of these in each rod.
And within each of these disks, you
have about 10,000 rhodopsin molecules.
There are several kinds of opcins, so-called.
Rhodopsins are the ones that you see in rods.
Then there are different kinds of opcins in cones.
And these are the photosensitive molecules
in your receptors so that when a photon comes in and connects
with and hits one of these molecules, they change shape.
And the simplest way of thinking about this
is to say that these molecules, these rhodopsin molecules,
come in two different shapes.
And these two different shapes are what we call very simply
those that are open and those that are sort of closed,
if you'll be describing the molecular shape.
And the easiest way to think of them
is that they are bleached or unbleached.
And so there are millions of these molecules.
And what is it, 10 million in each rod?
And you know how many rods there are in the average eye?
About 120 million, OK?
And about 5 or 6 million cones.
I mean, you're talking about unbelievable numbers.
It's just hard to comprehend.
But at any rate, the molecules here then
are in two different states, bleached and unbleached.
What that means is when a molecule shifts from being
unbleached to bleached as a result of a photon hitting it,
that changes the overall, I'm talking about, of course,
hundreds of molecules typically, the overall degree
of de- and hyperpolarization of the cell.
And that will then determine whether this cell is going
to communicate the next elements below.
And I'll describe that in much more detail in just a minute.
But it gives you an idea of how unbelievably complex this is.
Yet another complexity is that you
have this huge number of rods, OK?
But if you think about it, would these rods
be there in each, sorry, in these rods,
would each of these disks persist for a lifetime?
I know, say the average lifetime is 80 or 90 years.
Would these same guys exist in the eye all the time?
Well, the answer is no.
What happens is there's yet another process, amazingly,
that replaces in steps these disks in the rods.
Usually a few disks have a few days.
So it's a constant dynamic process keeping your rods,
if not your whole body, young, so to speak.
All right.
So anyway, this gives you sort of a crude sense
of a complexity of this system.
But now we are going to shift over and talk
and talk about the retinal ganglion cells.
And then we'll come back and we'll
talk about in a bit more detail about the pre-retinal
ganglionic elements.
Here is a set of pictures created by a wonderful scientist
called Poyak showing you different classes of types,
if you will, of retinal ganglion cells.
The top row here had been named because of the small size
and the small dendritic arbors had been named midget cells.
Whereas these ones below, some of them at least,
are much, much bigger and have much larger dendritic arbors,
as you can see here, have been called parasol cells.
And why they've been called parasol cells
I'll explain to you in just a minute.
Now this set of pictures was created by the Golgi stain
that I mentioned to you before that was invented by Golgi
and extensively studied by Cajal.
And for this incredible work, they
had done a lot of it on the retina.
They received the Nobel Prize in 1906.
So what this disclosed then, an initial view,
was that there are different classes of retinal ganglion
cells.
And so therefore, the big question came up,
why do we have different classes of cells
like the retinal ganglion cells?
What do they do?
Well, initially, some people, again, which is good,
I think one should be resistant to change in new ideas
until they were really proven well.
Some people argued that eyes just continue.
But then it became evident that these
are indeed different classes.
And I will present some evidence to prove that.
So there are actually quite a number
of different classes of retinal ganglion cells
that perform different jobs.
We're going to try to understand what
are the different jobs they perform.
And we're going to concentrate mostly
on these midget and parasol cells
because they by far are the most numerous in the retina.
And make a major, major contribution to all of vision.
All right, so now let's look at the physiology
of retinal ganglion cells.
Now that we know we have these different kinds of ganglion
cells, how do we find out what they do?
Well, what was recognized in the early portions
of the 20th century, that to find out what these cells do
one needs to study their activity.
And to study their activity, what
was developed after many different trials
is to either record from individual axons
or to use a microelectrode that you could put into the eye
and record from individual cells and see what they do.
Well, the first person who did this was Kaffir Hartlein.
And for the beautiful work he had done,
he received the Nobel Prize in 1967.
Now what he did, he was a tremendous surgeon.
And so what he did, he did this in primitive animals
like frogs, he would take the optic nerve
and he would dissect one fiber from the optic nerve,
hook it up, and record electrically from it.
And then what he would do, he would
shine a light into the eye, move it around
until the cell generated action potentials.
That was just a very small region because, as I've mentioned,
each cell in the retina, each ganglion cell,
only sees a teeny, teeny little portion of the visual field.
So that's how he did his experiments.
And he made some really remarkable discoveries
which further then were elaborated
by using slightly different methods.
A slightly different method, first of all,
was to put a microelectrode into the eye.
And I've mentioned that to you before.
The initial microelectrode was a very fine tube of glass
which was heated and then pulled until the tip was only
about a micron in diameter, which enabled you
to record from individual cells in the retina
or for that matter anywhere in the brain.
Now, another change in the methods that emerged
is that instead of shining light directly into the eye,
people use reflected light because in the world, most
of what we see is reflected light.
We don't get, of course, nowadays this
has changed a little bit because we have computers
and we have a TV which was set up in such a way as to mimic
reflected light, if you will.
But in the natural world, for the most part,
we see reflected light.
All right, so when this was done,
this initial work that was done by Keffer Heartline, for which
she received a Nobel Prize, that he discovered
three major classes of cells based on that recording of his,
which he called, first of all, on-cells,
secondly off-cells, and the thirdly, on-off cells.
Now, the on-cells were those which
when you shone light into their so-called receptive field
area, they would discharge vigorously.
You turn the light on here, and you
can see the on-cell fires.
An off-cell, on the other hand, fired
when you turned off the light using this particular method.
And on-off cells were those which fired both to the onset
and the termination of the light.
And that's why they were called and are still
called to this day on and off cells.
So that was an incredible discovery
and has created a major evolution in the study
of the visual system.
All right, so now, doing this kind of work in more detail,
using especially mostly reflected light,
several other major discoveries were made.
A fellow at Harvard in his later years, originally
at Johns Hopkins, did experiments
carefully studying the receptive field structure
of these cells.
He would record, in this case, with microelectrodes
from a single cell, a gamma ganglion cell,
and then see how it responded when you fiddled around
with the light in the receptive field.
So imagine, then, that the eye is fixed.
It's looking out.
You're putting an electrode into, in this case,
into the eye or wherever you put it.
And then you can use lights, maybe like a projector,
move it around to find out where the receptive field is.
And then you can present, say, a small spot of light,
or you make it a big spot, make it different colors,
and so on and so on.
So when this was done, a remarkable discovery
was made by Kufler, namely that the so-called on and off
cells were not just responding to the onset
and termination of light.
Instead, what they did was they responded vigorously
to a small spot in the center of the so-called receptive field.
But if you use a large spot like that,
there was much less of a response.
And that was true also for the off cells
and for the on-off cells.
So the surround we can think of as being inhibitory
with respect to the center.
And so the big question was, why on earth
did this complex arrangement evolve
of having cells that have not only an excitatory center
but also have an inhibitory surround?
And now I'm going to let you think about this for a minute.
And eventually, I will tell you as to why we
have this organization.
Because we are going to devote a whole session
to the on and off systems and also a complete session
to the midget and parasol cells.
And that's when we are going to discuss this in detail.
The important thing, as you learn about these things,
is to be an active thinker.
And if something comes up and say, well, why did this happen?
Why did that happen?
Why is this?
Why is that?
When you actively think about that,
then it becomes interesting.
And also, once the answers come, it
becomes insightful and exciting to understand it.
OK, so now, a series of investigators
did experiments in which they did labeling of just the cell
bodies in the retina and did what is called a hole mount.
What's a hole mount?
You take the retina, you flatten it out,
then you look at this whole layout through a microscope.
And if you label them these cells,
and this was a so-called nistel stain that
stains the cell bodies, but doesn't stain the processes
like the dendrites or the exons, what they found
was that if you did this quantitatively,
they could distinguish three very distinct different
classes of cells.
Turned out later that there were more than three.
But in this case, just doing it crudely like that,
you can see those big cells.
That one, that one, that one, that one, that one,
and so on.
Maybe one out of seven or eight in this sample
are these huge cells.
And then you have some smaller cells,
and then you also have some tiny cells.
And if you did this quantitatively,
they argued that they formed distinct, separate populations.
They were not a continuum.
So then, that, of course, is a basic requirement
to prove that, indeed, these are different classes of cells
that probably perform different jobs.
So what can you do to prove this further?
Well, subsequent to this kind of work,
people began to look at another interesting question
about how these retinal ganglion cells send their signals
to the central nervous system.
And it's been discovered not just in the retina,
but in many other parts of the human and animal body
that the rapidity with which an axon can send its action
potentials down from one location to the next,
from the cell body, say, to the axon terminals,
is very much depends on the size of the cell
and the size of the axon.
So if you have a small cell and a very thin axon,
the conduction is slower than if you have a big cell
and a big axon.
So if that's the case, people argued
that if you were to take the optic nerve
and stimulate it at one site and a little base down,
maybe back towards the retina, record
and see what kind of overall general, not action potentials,
but overall activation takes place.
And when that was done, amazing discovery was made.
In this case, you can see we have two major dips here.
This is time.
Here is electrical stimulation.
Here is the activation of hundreds and hundreds of fibers.
And it shows that they form distinct groups, a very rapidly
conducting group, a slow conducting group,
and a very slow, more diffuse group.
So then it was subsequent, I'll talk about that later,
it was subsequently established that these very rapidly
conducting axons come from the so-called parasol cells.
The medium conducting ones come from the midget cells.
All right?
I'll tell you exactly how that was established.
But now that has become a solid fact.
OK.
So now, if you go back to the anatomy of these cell types,
if you look at them at equivalent distances
of eccentricity, OK, 1, 3, and 5.7 degrees,
here are examples of the midget cell dendritic arbors.
So again, this is a whole mind.
You're looking straight down at the cell, all right?
You can see these are very, very constricted dendritic arbors.
Now, by contrast, the parasol cells
have much, much larger, three times larger in diameter
dendritic arbors.
And now I can tell you, which I deferred before,
is that if you look at these, the reason
they're called parasol cells is what?
Because it looks like an umbrella, OK?
So this looks like an umbrella.
And of course, that's parasol.
So that's why they are called parasol cells.
And these guys, most of us interesting,
are called midget cells because they're midget.
They're small.
All right, so that then established,
this work was done just 20 years ago,
it was established that you have indeed
these two very, very distinct populations of cells.
So now the big question came up, why do we have on and off
cells?
Why do we have midget and parasol cells?
And as I say, we are going to discuss this in considerable
detail.
But let me just give you a crude introduction.
If you look at the parasol cell, obviously,
because of the huge dendritic arbors,
they have large, relatively speaking, much larger receptor
feels three times bigger than midget cells.
The midget cells are so specific that each cell
in central retina, its input for the excitatory center
from just one single cone.
Now, what does that mean?
But I didn't emphasize before, but I'm sure you all
know that we have three major classes of cones, which
some people call red, green, and blue.
And then when you say that, the real aficionados say,
come on, you can't say that.
You're supposed to say short, medium, and long wavelength
sensitive neurons.
But we'll just call them red, green, and blue.
Now, the reason then is that the center of one class of midget
cells gets included only from red cones,
another from green cones, and some from blue cones.
I'll show that in more detail in a minute.
So we have these three subtypes.
And so therefore, we can say that the midget cells,
because they're so teeny, they should
be able to see fine detail.
And because of this wiring, they should
be able to tell you about color.
By contrast, if you look at the parasol cells,
they get a mix of inputs, both in the center and the surround.
So it's unlikely that they can tell you about color.
And we'll examine that in much more detail soon.
All right, so now, the other interesting thing
about this system is it makes you speculate as to why we have
them, and we'll elaborate on that,
is that the midget system, when you turn on the light,
when you shine a small spot in the center receptive field,
gives you a fairly sustained response for the brief time
that was maybe a second or two.
But the parasol system gives you only a burst,
like that, instead of a sustained response.
So think about that.
Say, why would we have two systems which are not
only different in size, but also different in the profile
of their responses?
And then, once you have this question in your mind,
then you'll be eager to find out when we talk about that time
after next.
OK, so now let's go back to the beginning here
and talk about the photoreceptors
in just a bit more detail, so we can get a better picture of it.
Here, as I've mentioned to you before, in the fovea,
you have very, very tightly packed cone photoreceptors.
They're almost hexagonal in shape rather than round.
They're so tightly packed.
But then, when you go five degrees out,
you first of all see that the cones got to be much larger.
And now, you have an intermixture of rods there
that you can see.
So in this region, you can process
both information at low illumination levels
and high illumination levels, whereas here,
as Kaffir Hotline had proven, you can only
see under fairly right normal illumination conditions.
OK, so now, if you go even further out in the retina,
this is a beautiful three-dimensional looking
picture, this shows the rods and the cones in the periphery.
Many, many more rods per unit area,
and the cones have gotten even bigger.
And so obviously, the ability for the cones
to process fine information has been degraded as a result.
Now again, as I've mentioned to you before,
we have in humans, there are about 120 million rods,
now five million cones, in each retina.
OK, so now, if you look at the overall distribution,
this is not too important, you can
see that as you go away from the fovea,
there's a very rapid decline in the number of cones.
That's a hash line.
And then there are no rods in the fovea,
but they increase rapidly, and then they fall off.
So that's the overall distribution.
And therefore, you can see fine detail in the center,
and you're very sensitive for night vision,
and not in a far periphery, but sort of in the mid section
here, anywhere between 20 and 40 degrees from the fovea.
Now let me remind you, because I'm sure you know all this
already, a few facts.
Some of this, I will just write down a couple of these things.
First of all, what is a degree of visual angle?
That's a good question.
What does it mean on the retinal surface?
Just let me give you an interesting mnemonic.
If you stick out your arm like that,
and you look at your thumbnail, that
imprints one degree of visual angle on the retinal surface.
OK?
Now we are going to talk a lot about very small measurements.
And so when we talk about small measurements,
I mentioned already that the tip of a microelectro
is about one micron.
And what is a micron?
Anybody know?
Yes?
10 to the negative 6.
OK.
One micron is 1,000th of a millimeter.
OK?
Now, talking about that in terms of millimeters, which
you are going to do a lot, that's the greatest convention,
we need to also know what is the relationship between inches
and millimeters and centimeters.
OK, so if you take one inch.
You all know what an inch is, I guess.
Roughly, if you look at your thumbnail again,
it's maybe a little bit under an inch.
OK?
Now, one inch equals 2.54 millimeters.
So that's a very interesting mnemonic to remember.
So whenever you look at various things
and try to understand size, you may
need to make that conversion, especially if you have always
thought about things in terms of inches.
Yes?
I think you mentored centimeters.
What?
Did you mean to write centimeters?
You're right.
2.5 centimeters.
Yeah, 254 millimeters.
You're right.
OK, sorry about that.
Very good, thank you for pointing that out.
OK, so now, what we are going to do next
is we're going to move on, and I'll
tell you another clever experiment that had been done.
These people here, McCrane and all,
developed a method which enabled them to selectively
label the blue cells in the retina.
And this shows a picture of that.
All the rest of them are red and green cells.
So only one out of eight cones is in the foveal area,
near foveal area.
I should say this is both the foveal and the periphoveal,
is black, the rest of them are red and green cones.
OK?
Now, let's become specific about the facts here,
and tell you first of all that one degree, roughly one
degree, which I pointed out is like a thumb,
it comprises 200 micro on the retinal surface.
The inter-cone distance in the foveal is only 2.4 micro,
whereas per square millimeter, I already mentioned this,
you have about 200,000 cones.
You go out five degrees, that reduces 10-fold.
And then, this I pointed out to you several times,
that's a good thing to remember.
And one thing I haven't mentioned before
is that if you look at a 12-front ladder, I,
when you look at it at 23 centimeters,
that activates about 80 cones.
So that gives you sort of a handle
on what is the nature of activation there.
And I already said that several times,
namely that each rod has 1,000 discs,
and each disc in it has 10,000 molecules.
OK.
And as I've just mentioned, one out of eight cones is blue,
the other are fairly equally numbered,
but varies from person to person.
OK.
So now, we are going to tell you about yet another experiment.
And in this, this is an incredibly clever experiment
that was carried out by Ursula Drager.
At that time, when she did this beautiful experiment,
she did this at Harvard, at Harvard Medical School.
And what she did was this.
She took the words fiat lux, put it on a screen,
and exposed it to a dark-adapted animal,
and the animal being a mouse.
OK.
And then, her procedure enabled her
to label, using a monoclonal antibody label,
those cells that had been activated by fiat lux.
OK.
So this is then what she, this is the actual retina,
flat-mount retina, showing you what had been activated.
Now, that's remarkable, beautiful.
And she came and gave a talk here at MIT maybe about 15
years ago.
And when she presented this picture,
one of the students, it wasn't any of you, I guess,
raised her hand and was very upset.
But, but, but, but, but.
And so Ursula said, yes?
So what do you think this patient, this subject asked?
This listener asked.
Well, this was a very active thinker.
This person said, but, but, but, was this image
right set up on the retinal surface?
That was a question.
And Ursula Drager said, no, it was upside down.
I just rotated it 180 degrees so you can see it.
All right.
Well, interestingly enough, there were times
when this became an issue.
First of all, before, people knew about lenses,
and that lenses turn images upside down.
And, and secondly, because many people
didn't believe that the images are upside on the retina.
I mean, if images are upside down on the retina,
they're upside down on the, on your brain,
and yet the world is right side up.
What's going on?
So I would say about eight or 10 years ago,
I was asked to review a paper for a high-visibility journal.
I can't name the journal.
In which the investigator very, very vociferously
proclaimed that we have all been wrong
and that the images are right set up on the retina after all.
So what was his proof?
Well, his proof was that he took an ox eye, a slotted ox's eye,
and cut out a little piece in the back of the eye
and put a translucent piece of paper over it,
and then presented a stimulus out there.
And when you looked at the back of the eye,
the translucent part, the image was right side up.
A little bit blurred, but right side up.
And so he felt that he proved that images are right side up
on the retina after all.
Well, I was flabbergasted, and it took me quite a while
to figure out why this guy got what he got,
because he'd obviously got what he got.
So can you guys think of any reason for this?
How come he got what he got?
Wait, what did he do?
He took the eye, and the back he cut out a little opening,
and put a transparency over it.
So then anything came in there, you could see what
would have been normally on the retina surface.
I mean, it was a clever experiment.
No question about that.
So what was wrong with the experiment?
Well, I'll tell you.
What was wrong with the experiment
goes back to what I told you before about the way
the lens works.
The lens works so that when you look at something close,
the muscles of the lens are such that it makes the lens fat.
And when the muscles relax, it makes the lens thick.
Sorry, thin.
So that means, just to be graphic about it,
is that if you have a thick lens,
you have a short focal length.
And if you have a thin lens, you have a much longer focal
length like that.
So now, if you look at the back of the eye here,
where the photoreceptors are, in this case,
it looks like it's with the upside down.
But if they were in the same distance here,
it would be blurred, and it would remain right side up,
just like it is with a magnifying glass.
So what this guy didn't know is the rule of how the muscle works
in the eye to control the lens.
And when the animal was killed, it no longer
had the lens at the proper focal depth.
And therefore, the image was right side up.
So therefore, guess what happened?
I wrote back to this high visibility journal saying,
that this guy is wrong for this reason.
So that was certainly an interesting experience,
and that's why I managed to learn a little bit about how
the lens works in the eye, which is a remarkable way it works,
since it's so totally different from what
we are familiar with when it comes to cameras.
OK, so now let's go to the next step, one down
from your photoreceptors.
And we come to the so-called bipolar cells.
Here's a series of pictures of the so-called cat bipolar
cells.
And what was discovered is that the bipolar cells,
here in the outer plexiform layer,
they connect with the photoreceptors.
And the inner plexiform layer, their external projections,
are such that in the upper layer here, which is IPL layer A,
the cells there are off cells.
And the ones that project below this here
are the so-called on cells.
So there's a separation of the so-called on and off cells
at the bipolar cell level in the manner in which they connect.
And so therefore, those ganglion cells that connect with these
are off ganglion cells.
And those that connect with these are on ganglion cells.
All right, so that's basically out of the bipolar cells.
And then when you come to the horizontal cells,
here's an example, a beautiful example,
of a proscienielo-labeled horizontal cell.
And if that is then analyzed in detail,
it looks something like this.
This particular cell has 15 connections
with the photoreceptors.
And these cells, I might as well anticipate.
We'll talk about that in more detail later.
They play a central role in providing the surrounding
inhibition that I described to you
for those retinal ganglion cells.
Then if you proceed to the amocrine cells,
and again, things are so complicated,
the numerous, numerous amocrine cells, different types.
And they have been studied extensively.
They're more than 20.
And here's a clever experiment I thought I'd point out to you.
What you can do here, if you look at the so-called cholinergic
amocrine cells, that's one class,
you can selectively label them because they're cholinergic.
And here's an example of what all those lighter blue ones
are your cholinergic cells.
And then what you can do, you can put this under a microscope.
And then you can lower a microelectrode
into one of these cells, just like I've done here.
And if you look at this closely, this
is not the best of pictures.
This is the labeled, again, close to a yellow labeled cell,
amocrine cell.
You can see it has all these processes.
So then if you look at this on the microscope
on the high quality, you can draw these out.
And this is what they look like.
So this is a cholinergic cell.
This is another type.
It's just called A2, which has a lot to do with rods.
And then we have another class called open immunergic.
I'm not going to go into detail about it.
But you can see that each of these now,
scientific methods enabled you to specify
what these amocrine cells are like.
And the basis of that, people have come up
with ideas what the amocrine system does.
Now we come to the crux of things in the last few minutes.
We're going to talk about the electrical responses
in the retina.
Now this is going to be, again, fairly complicated.
This work, again, remarkable work, which in my view
merits a Nobel Prize, but it has not yet been awarded,
to John Dowling at Harvard.
And let me just introduce this by telling you
how they went about this experiment.
They realize that the cells in the retina are very, very small.
And so it's very difficult to record from them intercellulately.
You have to do that if you want to be able to label them
anatomically.
And so they looked around for a species of animal
that had large cells in the retina.
And they discovered after a lot of search
that the so-called mud puppy and the necturus maculosis
is an animal that has unusually large retinal ganglion cells.
Then they developed a technique of removing the eye
from this animal and putting it into a dish,
because that makes it real stable.
And then they were able to put an electrode in there,
define what the cells did functionally
by shining light on and looking at their activity.
And then they were able to label the cell
by injecting a labeling substance.
So that's what they did.
So here is the description of that arrangement.
Here you have an inverted mud puppy retina.
And here you have a DC recording electrode.
And what you do then, you look at it in a oscilloscope.
And at this point, the cell is entered by the DC recording.
And then once it's inside, cells inside are negatively
charged with respect to the surround, usually
up to about 70 millivolts.
In this case, I have 50 millivolts labeled.
And so once you're inside the cell,
you see a sudden drop to a minus level.
And then if the cell discharges an action potential,
then you see that, of course, in the oscilloscope.
And then you can study this cell in all kinds of detail
as to how it responds, what it responds, and so on,
to determine what its characteristics are.
So then, when they did that, they
made the following central discoveries.
They discovered, first of all, that receptors
all hyperpolarized the light.
Now, this is the opposite of what you would have thought,
because the principle of the way cells operate,
and I'm sure you know all this, but I will also
describe it in a bit more detail in a minute,
cells, when they hyperpolarize, they
are less likely to cause a release in neurotransmitters.
If they depolarize, they will increase
the likelihood of neurotransmitters being released.
And by the way, the neurotransmitter for these receptors
is glutamate.
And also, which I should emphasize here,
is that the receptors never give action potentials.
They only give graded potentials.
And that's also true for the horizontal cells
and the bipolar cells.
Now, they found that all receptors
hyperpolarized the light, meaning
that they activate subsequent elements in the retina
when it gets darker out there, rather than when it gets lighter.
Which is the opposite that we all would have expected.
Same thing for the horizontal cells.
But then, when you come to bipolar cells,
suddenly you find that there are two different classes.
One class which mimics what the receptors do.
The other class that does the opposite.
And so the bipolar cells of these two types,
this type has called sine conserving synapses.
And this type has sine inverting synapses.
Now, anachronous cells come in various types.
And some give action potentials.
And ganglion cells all give action potentials.
So to go through this again, all receptors
hyperpolarized the light, horizontal cells,
or hyperpolarized the light, bipolar cells hyperpolarized
and have depolarized.
Now, this is accomplished by the way.
I'll go into that in more detail later.
By virtue of having different kinds
of neurotransmitter receptor sites.
And I'll talk about that in a lot of detail
when you talk about the unenolved cells.
OK, and then we have the anachronous cells,
some hyperpolarized, some depolarized,
and some give action potentials.
And all ganglion cells give action potentials.
So that is a major, major discovery.
And not only major, but totally unexpected
from what one would have thought.
So now, let me just explain this in a bit more detail.
If you go inside a cell, then if the cell is activated,
it can be either get what you see
as an excitatory postsynaptic potential, which
goes from minus to what's plus.
Or you can get an IPSP, an inhibitory postsynaptic
potential.
And this discovery was made by Echols,
which was a remarkably discovery in which he received
the Nobel Prize some years back.
All right, so now, if we look at those cells which
give action potentials, what happens
is when you get an EPSP, that's why
it's called excitatory postsynaptic potential,
then you increase the likelihood that an action
potential is generated.
That will send its signal down the axon
to the next location of the cells.
All right, so that's the basic process.
So again, to reiterate, photoreceptors hyperpolarize
the light.
Therefore, glutamate is released when
there is a decrease in illumination,
the opposite of what anyone would have expected.
All right, so that, I think, brings us
to what I wanted to cover today.
I'll wait until next time to talk
about the lateral genetic net nucleus, which is very brief.
But let me go through the photoreceptor basics again.
All photoreceptors hyperpolarize the light.
Depolarization of the photoreceptor releases glutamate.
Photon absorption by the photopigment results
in isomerization of the chromophore from 11, 6 to 11
trends.
This is what I told you to think about in a very simple
fashion to say that the photoreceptor molecules,
rhodopsin in this case, either is bleached or unbleached.
So once it's bleached, further light has no effect on it.
And at any point, given whatever the level of illumination is,
a certain percentage of these rhodopsin molecules
are bleached, and a certain percentage is unbleached.
The darker it is, the more are unbleached.
All right, then we have these two classes
that we talked about, the on and the off cells
that we will discuss in some detail.
The synaptic junction of bipolar is assigned conserving,
as I had just said.
And that of the unbipolar is assigned inverting.
Now, the unbipolar receptor is, I should mention that now,
and I will deal with it in detail, is called the M-glue R6.
Its activation leads to closing of channels
causing hyperpolarization.
So that's the basic layout, then, of the photoreceptors.
And I will now stop at this point.
And next time, you'll talk a little bit
about the nitrogenic nucleus.
And then we're going to move on to talk about the cortex.
And then if you look at your assignment sheet,
then you can see here that on September 16th,
we're going to talk about the on and off channels.
And then we'll deal in more detail
with these rather complex things, which
are pretty hard to remember about hyperpolarization,
depolarization, glutamate, glutamate, receptor sites,
and so on.
OK?
Thank you.